denisewakeman.com 2019-06-29

# Privacy Policy | Digital Marketing Guide for Authors & Online Entrepreneurs | Denise Wakeman

The Blog Squad, LLC a.k.a. Denise Wakeman, Adventures in Visibility and Marketing Trailblazers respects your privacy and is committed to protecting it through this Privacy Policy.

This Privacy Policy governs your access to and use of www.denisewakeman.com and www.marketingtrailblazers.co, including any content, functionality, and services offered on or through www.denisewakeman.com or www.marketingtrailblazers.co, whether as a guest or a registered user.

When accessing the website, the we will learn certain information about you, both automatically and through voluntary actions, you may take, during your visit. This policy applies to information we collect on the website and in email, text, or other electronic messages between you and the website.

Please read the Privacy Policy carefully before you start to use the Website.  **By using the Website or by clicking to accept or agree to the Terms of Use when this option is made available to you, you accept and agree to be bound and abide by the Privacy Policy.**  If you do not want to agree to the Privacy Policy, you must not access or use the Website.

## Who we are

The Blog Squad, LLC

Our website addresses are https://denisewakeman.com and https://www.marketingtrailblazers.co

## What personal data we collect and why we collect it

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

### Media

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

### Contact forms

The Website provides various places for users to provide information. We collect information that users provide by filling out forms on the Website, communicating with us via contact forms, responding to surveys, search queries on our search feature, providing comments or other feedback, and providing information when ordering a product or service via the Website.

We use the information you provide to us to deliver the requested product and/or service, to improve our overall performance, and to provide you with offers, promotions, and information.

Some contact forms are generated through LeadPages. Their privacy policy is available here: https://www.leadpages.net/privacy 

You contact information is stored via a secure account on Infusionsoft. Their privacy policy is here: https://www.infusionsoft.com/legal/privacy-policy

### Cookies and Pixels

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to save your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

Similar to other commercial websites, our website utilizes a standard technology called “cookies” and server logs to collect information about how our site is used. Information gathered through cookies and server logs may include the date and time of visits, the pages viewed, time spent at our site, and the websites visited just before and just after our own, as well as your IP address.

A cookie is a very small text document, which often includes an anonymous unique identifier. When you visit a website, that site’s computer asks your computer for permission to store this file in a part of your hard drive specifically designated for cookies. Each website can send its own cookie to your browser if your browser’s preferences allow it, but (to protect your privacy) your browser only permits a website to access the cookies it has already sent to you, not the cookies sent to you by other sites.

The Company reserves the right to use technological equivalents of cookies, including social media pixels. These pixels allow social media sites to track visitors to outside websites so as to tailor advertising messages users see while visiting that social media website. The Company reserves the right to use these pixels in compliance with the policies of the various social media sites.

### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracking your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

### Analytics

Google Analytics is used on this site to gather information so we can better understand traffic patterns and study trends on the site. Data is stored for 26 months.  The privacy policy for all Google products is here: https://policies.google.com/privacy/

### **Email Information**

If you choose to correspond with us through email, we may retain the content of your email messages together with your email address and our responses. We provide the same protections for these electronic communications that we employ in the maintenance of information received online, mail, and telephone. This also applies when you register for our website, sign up through any of our forms using your email address or make a purchase on this site. For further information see the email policies below.

### **Email Policies**

We are committed to keeping your e-mail address confidential. We do not sell, rent, or lease our subscription lists to third parties, and will not disclose your email address to any third parties except as allowed in the section titled Disclosure of Your Information.

We will maintain the information you send via e-mail in accordance with applicable federal law.

In compliance with the CAN-SPAM Act, all e-mails sent from our organization will clearly state who the e-mail is from and provide clear information on how to contact the sender. In addition, all e-mail messages will also contain concise information on how to remove yourself from our mailing list so that you receive no further e-mail communication from us.

Our emails provide users the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from us and our partners by reading the unsubscribe instructions located at the bottom of any e-mail they receive from us at any time.

Users who no longer wish to receive our newsletter or promotional materials may opt-out of receiving these communications by clicking on the unsubscribe link in the e-mail.

### ​ **How And Why We Collect Information**

The Company collects your information in order to record and support your participation in the activities you select. If you register to download digital products or resources, sign up for our blog post updates, and/or purchase a product from us, we collect your information. We use this information to track your preferences and to keep you informed about the products and services you have selected to receive and any related products and/or services. As a visitor to this Website, you can engage in most activities without providing any personal information. It is only when you seek to download resources and/or register for services that you are required to provide information.

If you are outside the European Union and opt to receive any free resources, participate in any free training programs, register for a webinar, register for a live event, register for a seminar, or purchase any products sold by the Company on this Website, we will automatically enroll you to receive our occasional updates. If you do not wish to receive these updates, you can unsubscribe anytime. We include an “unsubscribe” link at the bottom of every email we send. If you ever have trouble unsubscribing, you can send an email to hello@denisewakeman.com requesting to unsubscribe from future emails.

If you are in the European Union and opt to receive any free resources, participate in any free training programs, register for a webinar, register for a live event, register for a seminar, or purchase any products sold by the Company on this Website, we will only enroll you to receive our free email updates if you affirmatively consent to it. If you do not wish to receive these updates, you can unsubscribe anytime. We include an “unsubscribe” link at the bottom of every email we send. If you ever have trouble unsubscribing, you can send an email to hello@denisewakeman.com requesting to unsubscribe from future emails.

### **How Do We Use the Information That You Provide to Us?**

We use personal information for purposes of presenting our Website and its contents to you, providing you with information, providing you with offers for products and services, providing you with information about your subscriptions and products, carrying out any contract between you and the Company, administering our business activities, providing customer service, and making available other items and services to our customers and prospective customers.

From time-to-time, we may use the information you provide to us to make you offers to purchase products and services provided by third parties in exchange for a commission to be paid to us by such third parties. Should you opt to take part in such promotions, the third parties will receive your information.

From time-to-time, we may use the information you provide to us to display advertisements to you that are tailored to your personal characteristics, interests, and activities.

## Who we share your data with

Third party providers with whom the Company shares and stores data in the course of conducting business, include:

  * Google – GSuite products and Analytics <https://policies.google.com/privacy/>
  * Cloudflare <https://www.cloudflare.com/privacyshield/>
  * Gravatar – <https://automattic.com/privacy/>
  * Facebook <https://m.facebook.com/about/privacyshield>
  * A2 Hosting –  <https://www.a2hosting.com/about/policies#Terms-Of-Service>
  * Infusionsoft CRM & Shopping cart & payment processing – https://www.infusionsoft.com/legal/privacy-policy
  * Zoom web conferencing –  https://zoom.us/privacy
  * Stripe – https://stripe.com/us/privacy
  * PayPal – https://www.paypal.com/us/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full
  * Mighty Networks (host for Marketing Trailblazers community) – https://mightynetworks.com/privacy_policy
  * Hubspot CRM (managing prospects and leads) – https://legal.hubspot.com/privacy-policy
  * Billy accounting system – https://billyapp.com/privacy-policy/
  * Deadline Funnel – https://deadlinefunnel.com/tos
  * LeadPages – https://www.leadpages.net/privacy
  * Carbonite (cloud backup) – https://www.carbonite.com/terms-of-use/privacy-policy/
  * Dropbox (cloud backup) – https://www.dropbox.com/privacy
  * PCloud (cloud backup) – https://www.pcloud.com/privacy_policy.html
  * Book Like a Boss – https://booklikeaboss.com/privacy
  * Typeform – https://termsandconditions.typeform.com/to/L9Crcj

## How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

We keep contact form entries for a minimum of six months or until you request to have email address removed from our email list; analytics records are kept for 26 months, and customer purchase records for ten years.

## What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

If you are within the European Union, you are entitled to certain information and have certain rights under the General Data Protection Regulation. Those rights include:

We will retain the any information you choose to provide to us until the earlier of (a) you ask us to delete the information, (b) our decision to stop using our existing data providers, or (c) the Company decides that the value in retaining the data is outweighed by the costs of retaining it.

You have the right to request access to your data that the Company stores and the rights to either rectify or erase your personal data.

You have the right to seek restrictions on the processing of your data.

You have the right to object to the processing of your data and the right to the portability of your data.

To the extent that you provided consent to the Company’s processing of your personal data, you have the right to withdraw that consent at any time, without affecting the lawfulness of processing based upon consent that occurred prior to your withdrawal of consent.

You have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority that has jurisdiction over issues related to the General Data Protection Regulation.

We require only the information that is reasonably required to enter into a contract with you. We will not require you to provide consent for any unnecessary processing as a condition of entering into a contract with us.

## Where we send your data

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

We employ commercially reasonable methods to ensure the security of the information you provide to us and the information we collect automatically. This includes using standard security protocols and working only with reputable third-party vendors.

Email is not recognized as a secure medium of communication. For this reason, we request that you do not send private information to us by email. However, doing so is allowed, but at your own risk. Some of the information you may enter on our website may be transmitted securely via a secure medium known as Secure Sockets Layer, or SSL. Credit Card information and other sensitive information is never transmitted via email.

The Company may use software programs to create summary statistics, which are used for such purposes as assessing the number of visitors to the different sections of our site, what information is of most and least interest, determining technical design specifications, and identifying system performance or problem areas.

For site security purposes and to ensure that this service remains available to all users, the Company uses software programs to monitor network traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or otherwise cause damage.

## Contact us:

Denise Wakeman  
11241 Camarillo Street, Unit 6  
North Hollywood, CA 91602, USA

denise@denisewakeman.com

### Effective as of May 18, 2018
